Canada had made gay marriage legal so
Thea and Edie go to Toronto and they'd
get married in front of six buddies they
Exchange rings and Edie and theater are
like whoa this feels different to truly
be married like there's a tangible
difference this is not that's
very sweet to be like I'm to flaunt the
laws yeah those laws
[Music]
hello today we're going to talk about
Carl Sagan and
foreign
in 1977 the outer planets were in
precise alignment and the guys at Nassau
were like we could send up to spacecraft
Voyager 1 and Voyager 2 that could swing
around each planet to collect data and
conduct research and to take pictures
and to possibly no for sure Ridley be
flung into deep space let's some
up so NASA comes to Carl Sagan
who's a famous astronomer astrophysicist
and they're like hey man would you like
to lead a team that creates the message
a mixtape
for all of humanity that we cast into
the cosmic ocean
girls Sagan is like Absa
lutely let's put together a cake
ass team he hires Anne Tran to be their
creative director she's a journalist
she's a writer she's amazing so they
talked about how to like send the
message and an eight-track tape came up
at one point but Carl was like this
thing is gonna get up in your
Cadillac What's it gonna do at 35 000
miles an hour for a billion years in
deep space so these guys at Nassar are
looking at each other and they were like
we could do this on a record a copper
record played in Gold wolf played this
thing in Gold what do we care
we're the United States government
ah
weirdness
so Annie and Carl sat around his kitchen
table for hours on end going over what
should be included in the golden record
they talked about all that was best
about Humanity what was beautiful it was
poetic they looked at each other and
said let's include whale sounds let's
include Thunder let's include pictures
of drinking and licking and swallowing
and biting and eating
should swell underneath and Annie is
looking at Carl thinking this will
outlive ourselves Maybe by a billion
years
[Music]
is outlive a word
they begin working on a record they
recorded a child's voice that's like
greetings from the children of planet
Earth they recorded a baby that was like
a kiss like
um Birds
has that been on this whole time
because I haven't lived since we started
filming okay where are we Sorry
Carl was like oh we have to represent
different eras of humanity
so Anne found a 2500 year old piece of
ancient Chinese music and she was like
oh my gosh that's some old ass music I
have to let Carl know this is the
greatest ever and she calls him doesn't
get him leaves a message hey it's Annie
I got it it's called flowing stream it's
an ancient piece of Chinese music most
exciting thing so far that we needed yes
it might sound like what plays under
your massage or whatever but it's
important and we needed it and you're
not here and it would be really cool if
you were here or whatever this is Annie
might have already said that goodbye
Carl calls her back and says I wish you
had left me this message a message
10 years ago and she was like what are
you talking about he was like I guess
you and me and she was like for Keeps
and he was like yeah and then they hung
up the phone and she was like Jesus what
is going on right now and the phone
rings again and he was like what's going
on and she was like I think we just got
engaged and he was like I think that's
100 cool with me
foreign
wrong pipe
sorry about that and they got engaged
over the phone having never shared a
kiss a romantic moment nothing it just
started to get choked up and
um after their Declaration of love she
gets an idea Annie goes to Bellevue
Hospital gets all hooked up and she
meditates for an hour on her love for
Carl and they recorded her brain waves
and all of her thoughts were compressed
into a minute of an audio file that was
included in the golden record it sounds
like fireworks like
very cool
like that mm-hmm
so in 1977 the golden record was
launched into space
containing what we consider our very
best everything Carla and Annie went on
to create the cosmo series for PBS when
they were together for almost 20 years
before Carl died and to this day Annie
will be like whenever I feel sad or
depressed I think and and still they
move I mean that's crazy those
spacecraft carrying all of our best
science art greetings and the thoughts
of a woman has just fallen in love
[Music]
it's a beautiful story isn't it
yeah
hello I'm Drew drug
hello I'm Drew drogy and today we are
discussing Dog Day Afternoon the real
story we're from ruff ruff
it's 1971. and there's this guy named
John wadowitz he's a man about town he's
like I'm the he's at the Feast of
San Gennaro in Little Italy and he meets
this person named Elizabeth and they're
like hey hey wow wow and they're like
hey we're at the Feast of San Gennaro in
Little Italy let's have cannoli and ziti
and let's live life so John and
Elizabeth are in love with each other
but Elizabeth says I'm actually a trans
woman and John is like I'm cool with
that that's wonderful that makes sense
so they got married in an unofficial
ceremony in the village they're like I'm
in love with you oh my God I'm in love
with you and Elizabeth is like I need
sexual rear
she's like I need sexual reassignment
surgery this cost three thousand dollars
and John says we don't have three
thousand dollars in 2019 this drink cost
three thousand dollars yeah let's drink
it cheers so Elizabeth slips into a deep
depression and she goes into a mental
hospital and she's removed from John and
he misses her and he says I I want my
wife I want love my life I'm gonna give
her a sexual reassignment surgery I'm
gonna get that money for her I'm gonna
rob a bank I'm robbing a bank
so John recruits Salvatore naturale and
Robert westenberg and then they go see
The Godfather in The Godfather obviously
was starring Al Pacino and John Cazale
The Godfather got them going they're
like let's let's be criminals like like
the corleones they realize like we're
gonna need some guns so they get the
guns together the first bank they go to
is on the Lower East Side they get to
the bank they drop a shotgun it goes off
they're like guys everything's fine we
just dropped a shotgun it blew up we're
people let's just be people but we had
to go to another bank the next one's in
Queens they get out of the car they
immediately run into their mom's best
friend who is like Salvatore what's
going on how are you John nice to see
you what are you two boys doing together
and then they were thinking oh my God
it's our mother's best friend we gotta
get out of here
that's from Grace
they finally get to the Chase Manhattan
in Brooklyn but Robert westenberg sees a
cop car outside and gets spooked and he
leaves so it's just John and Sal that go
into the bank and they go in John yells
freeze this is a hold up I'm not alone
they pass the teller a note that says
put all your money in a bag or we're
gonna start shooting people this is an
offer you can't refuse and John's like
it's from The Godfather it's our
favorite movie
John and Sal they're about to leave when
a bunch of cop cars pull up John was
like you know what we're gonna leave
we're gonna keep everybody in this Bank
hostage boom this leads to a 14 hour
hostage standoff they're fumbling
bumbling the tellers are just freaking
out they're not hardened criminals they
don't really know what they're doing
Elizabeth asked John to stand down
ultimately Sal was killed and they
arrest John
so if you've seen the movie this is
where it ends but there's more to this
story so John goes to prison and he's
like oh I went through all this and
still my wife can't get what she needs
but a year later Hollywood producers
come into His jail cell he's like who
the are you guys what's going on
here and they're like we are Hollywood
producers we have a Hollywood movie we
would like to make about you we're gonna
give you a 70 of uh
seventy five hundred dollars and a one
percent profit share for your story and
he's like it's enough money for
Elizabeth's sex change and that's the
whole reason I got into this
I feel oh wasted anyway in 1975 Sydney
lumet directs Dog Day Afternoon it makes
46 million dollars it gets six Oscar
nominations and wins her best original
screenplay and it stars Al Pacino and
John cazell wow in prison he gets the
nickname the dog
um
foreign
visits him once a month Elizabeth gets
her sex change she was like honey I love
you and thank you John is in prison for
six years John gets out of prison and he
eventually sees dog Dan Fernando and
he's like holy this is Al Pacino
playing me and John Cazale is playing
Sal these are the people that I watch in
The Godfather playing me in the movie
how crazy is that so John and Elizabeth
eventually separate after a while but
they remain friends it's ultimately a
story about
an individual who sacrificed everything
that he was to help someone else I love
you too love you too Derek
yeah
it's not Dog Day Afternoon in Spanish
I love you I love you too dark
hello
my name is Allison Rich today we're
going to be talking about Edie Windsor
and the end of Doma the Defense of
Marriage Act cheers come on
could puke tonight you know what let's
do it
yeah let's just get it out of us so the
year is 1950. the place is the United
States of a at this point in history
it's not even legal to dance closely to
a person of the same sex so Edie Windsor
was a young lesbian she's like
oh I gotta keep my personal life private
because this is the past and the past is
closed-minded
so then I'm talking about gay stuff
so then Edie is in Greenwich Village and
she notices a beautiful leggy brunette
she goes hey
[Music]
are you can I dance with you the woman
goes hello my name is Thea spire and yes
that's a great name we've got Edie
Windsor and the Aspire two like cool
lesbian names yeah you know and then
Edie goes is your dance card full which
is an old-timey way of being like you
single and she goes it is now meaning
I'm ready
they have poles in them yes balls
worlds so then they date and they
fall in love but then on June 28th 1969
she encounters The Stonewall riots where
gay people were being out and proud
about who they were amid this police
raid at the Stonewall Inn so she goes
home and she's like Thea there's a big
riot at Stonewall about gay rights maybe
this is the moment that we should come
out and and and tell the world who we
really are so she's like I don't know
that's really risky maybe not so Edie
and Thea are like you know we're not
revolutionaries we're just two ladies
we're in love and like to dance and
we're gonna be private about it and they
do that for the next 30 years that's a
long time and the thing that they really
bonded over was dancing in any situation
their bodies could always connect
through dance and it's about 2007 now
enthia was in a wheelchair with Ms Theo
was like I want to get married by this
time Canada had made gay marriage legal
so Thea and Edie go to Toronto and then
get married in front of six buddies they
Exchange rings and Edie and theater are
like whoa this feels different to truly
be married like there's a tangible
difference this is not that's
very sweet to me like I to flaunt the
laws yeah those laws so in 2009 Thea
dies and Edie is there in the hospital
and she's like you know what I had good
life we had a beautiful love what more
could I ask for and then knock knock
the U.S government says hey
so your friend Thea left you a bunch of
property money assets and we don't
recognize that because you're two ladies
it's not like you were married so we're
gonna tax you on the order of half a
million dollars and Edie goes you
know we were married and this is
discriminating Nation I'm gonna call a
bunch of lawyers I'm gonna call a bunch
of gay rights activists
um so then she says excuse me I was in a
relationship with this woman for forever
we got married in Toronto this is legit
they're not recognizing their marriage
they're trying to tax the out of me
and the lawyers and activists are like
yeah that's Doma you know since 1996
this law was enacted that says on a
federal level a marriage is between a
man and a woman and it's just undef
indefeatable undefeatable in you can't
do it but then Edie calls Roberta Robbie
Kaplan is her name Roberta Robbie Kaplan
her fun name is Robbie her name is
Roberta Kaplan and this one goes you
know know what I'll take you on you are
what marriage is about you two were
married for decades through sickness and
in health you're a sweet old woman
you're the perfect example of what gay
marriage can be so Roberta and Edie sue
the federal government and it goes all
the way to the Supreme Court and Edie
goes before them and says if my love
isn't real no love is real we
were together for so long
our love deserves to be recognized
wow
it's actually very classy
so on June 26 2013 Edie and her
supporters gather around a computer pops
up on the screen drama's
unconstitutional five to four and
everyone's heart
[Music]
if I cheer too hard to be my fans
she goes back to Stonewall and Greenwich
Village and crowds were gathered and
they went
and Edie thought to yourself wow years
ago when I walked past here during the
Stonewall riots me and Thea thought
we're not revolutionaries but here we
are years later and we are the
revolutionaries we're the face of what
gay marriage can be and Edie dances
One Last Dance
in the name of the love of her life
beer Sophia and Edie and Edie whoa
beautiful that's amazing thanks to this
one Brave woman and her belief in the
equality of her love gay marriage became
legal do you think in in memory of them
that you and I should dance we should
dance so close well can I
give you a good pack
one two three
foreign
[Music]